<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Press &#8211; Woodlands Cardio</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/press/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 19:08:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Interview with Dr. Patel</title>
		<link>/2013/09/09/angioplasty-interview/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[s w]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 16:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dr. Sanjaykumar Patel, MD, FACC practices diagnostic and interventional procedures at the Sadler Clinic in the Houston, Texas area. He was one of the first interventional cardiologists in the Houston area to use the transradial approach and has performed more than 1,000 transradial catheterizations. Dr. Patel earned his Bachelor of Medicine &#38; Bachelor of Surgery [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dr. Sanjaykumar Patel, MD, FACC practices diagnostic and interventional procedures at the Sadler Clinic in the Houston, Texas area. He was one of the first interventional cardiologists in the Houston area to use the transradial approach and has performed more than 1,000 transradial catheterizations.</p>
<p>Dr. Patel earned his Bachelor of Medicine &amp; Bachelor of Surgery from Smt. NHL Municipal Medical College, Gujarat University in India. He completed his Internal Medicine at New York Medical College, NY, where he served as Chief Resident in 2003-2004 and then completed a fellowship in Cardiovascular Medicine and Interventional Cardiology at St. Vincent’s Hospital and Medical Center in New York. He is board certified in Interventional Cardiology, Cardiovascular Diseases, Nuclear Cardiology, Echocardiography and Internal Medicine.</p>
<p>Dr. Patel now runs monthly transradial training courses in an effort to promote the use of the wrist approach. A complete listing of educational offerings for the transradial approach, including Dr. Patel&#8217;s upcoming courses, can be found on the <a href="http://www.ptca.org/radial/radial_training.html"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em>Transradial Training Courses</em></span></a> page in Angioplasty.Org&#8217;s <em><a href="http://www.ptca.org/radial/index.html"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Radial Access Center</span>.</a> </em></p>
<p>Read the entire article at <a title="Dr Patel Interview at Angioplasty.org" href="http://www.ptca.org/radial/interview_sanjay_patel.html" target="_blank">Angioplasty.org </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
